My name is Lucky Susu.
This is my first time to come to this church.
I was released from prison.
I want to thank God for what He has done in my life.
It happened like this:
I am wheelbarrow pusher in my market.
When people have a load to carry, I will carry it for them to the bus stop.
Some people will give me 100 naira, some will give me 150 or 200 naira.
In 2008, on the 9th of December, I brought two bags of rice and some tubers of yam to the bus stop.
Across the tarmac, they were some people gathered.
I crossed to see what was happening.
There was an old woman on the ground who a motor vehicle had hit.
She was bleeding.
I began to shout, that the people should rush to help this woman.
They said that the vehicle that had hit the woman had driven away
and said, "Don't you know, this is Lagos".
I felt for the woman and decided to try and save her life.
I took the money that I had suffered for to help my family
to take the woman in a taxi to hospital in Agota.
We reached the hospital but the woman died in the hospital.
Then, the doctor called the police and they arrested me.
They charged me with murder.
Last week, a man came to the prison on Friday.
When he came, he was wearing a Faith Bracelet on his wrist from Prophet T.B. Joshua.
I explained to the man that I did not steal or kill but they still kept me there.
I asked him to keep me in his prayers.
The man said that the Faith Bracelet he was wearing was from The SCOAN
and that I should hold his hand.
One of the 15 people I have given to.
The person quickly called me.
The Faith Bracelet
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You'll see the wise men - they are always wearing and praying with it.
We call it Faith Bracelet.
You count your faith.
If I am not here now, I am busy with it.
If I am inside the vehicle, if I am sitting down like you -
if I were the one sitting down now, I would be busy with it.
You would see me sitting down busy with it.
While talking to you, the divine nature of me is busy.
While Mr T.B. Joshua is talking to you, the divine nature will be busy counting faith.
Because a break in faith is a break in God.
That time, I was in the maximum security prison, at Ikoyi.
Then, they transferred me to another place
where they keep robbery suspects waiting for judgement.
My mind was telling me that the same thing would happen to me.
A prayer came to my mind, "God of T.B. Joshua, if You are really alive..."
- I was holding the Faith Bracelet.
"If You are really alive and You work, remove me from the problem I am in
because I am innocent".
When I finished the prayer, I waited until evening before I slept
and prayed the same prayer again.
That night when I slept, the man of God appeared to me in a dream.
He spoke to me and said, "My Child, God has heard your cry and you are innocent".
He said that I should keep on doing the good that I used to do and
that I should not resign myself to suffering.
He said I would go home the next day.
That was on Tuesday night, going to Wednesday morning last week.
At around after 3 am, before it reached 4 am,
I heard my name at the gate: "Susu".
My mind was telling me that they wanted to take me to kill me;
so, I went to hide in the lavatory and began to cry.
They came and dragged me outside and then said that I had no case to answer.
Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
After they left me when we got outside, I walked towards Oshodi.
When I arrived there, I explained myself to a woman who gave me 150 naira.
I collected the money, kept it and then used it to get here this morning.
When I reached here, I was wearing the clothes I wore in the prison.
They are here, inside this bag.
They are the clothes I was wearing while in prison.
I arrived here and asked them to allow me to enter the church but they refused.
I asked them if I could join the people under the canopy
but they didn't allow me to enter there.
Let's see the clothes you wore here from prison.
Lucky Susu
Faith Bracelet Testimony
The clothes are here as well as the slippers I was wearing.
After I got here and they did not allow me to enter,
I went to sit down by that red gate outside and began to cry.
As I was crying, this morning, a man approached me and asked me why I was crying.
I explained my situation to him.
The man asked me to follow him which I did.
He took me through the red gate.
He give me soap and water and told me not to cry anymore.
He told me to shower and took me to the bathroom.
When I finished showering, I wanted to put on the same trousers
when a man who was there told me that the man that brought me
had said that I should wait for him in the bathroom.
I waited and before 15 minutes were over, the man came.
He had gone to buy me new trousers, a new shirt and new sandals.
- The same man?
- Yes.
- Do you know the man?
- No.
- But if you see him, you will know him?
- Yes.
You will go and look for him.
The man then gave me 500 naira which is in my hand now.
He said I should put it in my pocket, that I shouldn't be left without any money.
He said I should hold it in case I wanted to buy anything.
Did you listen to what he said?
He said he was just coming from prison with those dirty wears.
On getting here, no one wanted to reckon with him.
They asked him to go and stay outside.
Suddenly a man just came and said, "Ah, what happened?
Why are you looking like that? Are you mental?"
He said, "No, I'm from prison".
The man took him, bought him a soap, took him to the bathroom,
bathed him, got him money, bought new clothes for him, gave him money and
carried him inside the church.
I think this man needs to be encouraged.
I don't know the man but we need to see the man.
He said while he was in the prison, last week, a man just walked into the prison.
He didn''t know whether he was one of the wardens or one of the preachers that preached to the prisoners.
He just encountered the man.
The man said, "Oh, what happened? Why are sitting quietly in dejection?"
He was able to narrate the story to the man,
"This is the reason why I am in here. I am innocent".
And the man said, "Yes. This bracelet with me, I want you to pray with me.
Let me remove it and put it on your hand and pray with you.
Just ask for your release.
Ask God to reveal to the authority the cause of your stay here.
Why you are here, so that they can know the truth. You will be released".
He removed it, wore it, prayed with the man and immediately...
He said that night after the prayer, he saw a vision
and a man came to him and said, "Look, you will be released".
The second day, he said the authority came and they called his name out.
That was how he was released.
And immediately he was released, he had to come to The Synagogue,
to come and share this testimony.
"Hey, I've never been to The Synagogue. I don't know a place called Synagogue."
But immediately he was released, he asked people around, "Where is The Synagogue?"
But the man that gave the bracelet could not wait; he just had to leave
because I know the man is going around everywhere to deliver people with the message.
Ok, maybe the man will be seeing it on Emmanuel TV now that this man is out.
So now he came here.
On getting here, with the uniform he wore in front of the church,
people were running from him because he looked tattered.
Somebody just came and said, "Look, why are you standing somewhere?
Are you mental? Do you want to go to the emergency?"
That was how the man rescued the situation.
Got him money to buy soap, took him to the bathroom, washed him,
got him new clothes, gave him money for feeding.
Can you go and look for the man, please.
Take him out and look for the man. Bring the man forward.
Please, he said he doesn't know the man but when he sees the man, he will know.
Let us see the man.
Wow! So we can still see a good Samaritan like this.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If God is aware of your situation, your situation will not kill you but prepare you.
Tell your neighbour: If God is aware of your challenges
your challenges will not destroy you but prepare you.
Your challenges could be imprisonment; they could be temptation of any kind.
Such a situation may be allowed to strengthen your desire and your determination for God.
If God is involved, who else is involved does not matter.
Tell your neighbour: If God is involved, who else is involved does not matter.
So brother, continue your goodness.
The Good Samaritan Who Helped Mr Susu
Rise up! Glory, glory!
Wow!
Is it the man? Glory be to God!
Mr Susu With The Man Who Helped Him
Who is this?
This is the man who bought the clothes for me.
- Is he the one that bought soap?
- Yes.
- Washed you?
- Gave you clothes?
- Yes.
- And gave you money?
Mr Susu With The Man Who Helped Him
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Brother, where did you see this man? Is he your brother?
No, sir. I saw him at the gate where he was crying.
He looked so dirty; so, I called him and listened to him.
I asked him, "Why are you like this?"
He told me that he was released last week from prison
and because of the way he looked, they didn't want him to enter the church.
I told him to follow me if that was the case.
I took him to the bathroom so he could shower and I got him a change of clothes.
- You bought him clothes?
- Yes, sir.
- You bought him soap?
- And you waited there until he finished bathing?
- Yes, sir.
What else did you do?
I then brought him inside the church.
The Man Who Helped Mr Susu
What is your purpose of doing this?
Daddy we need to follow your footsteps.
He is one of the head of security - one of the head.
If this man has surplus and he is one of the head of security, he will do charity with it.
He will be giving the needy a lot.
Whilst he is doing the job there, he is giving out financial support.
Wow. We pray what you are doing now shall be permanent.
Ha. You might have been doing this because this one is too obvious
that is why we are aware of it. You might have been doing it for so long.
I know this man. It is true; in was in our market,
pushing a wheelbarrow for many years.
- You know who?
- I know this man.
He is very quiet. He would push a wheelbarrow.
If people bought a lot of items, he would help them to carry them.
For many years, I had not seen him; I thought he had relocated
and didn't know he was in prison.
You heard it from the woman coming out from the midst of the congregation,
testifying that what this man is saying is nothing but the truth.
In the same market that the man mentioned, at mile 12,
they knew him at the market as someone who pushed local trolleys to carry loads for people.
When they did not see him after some time, they thought he had relocated to another market,
not knowing that he was in prison.
We are still coming back to that. Let's settle the Good Samaritan.
What this security has done now is telling the gentleman that
he should not stop doing good.
Because of what has happened to him, he should not stop.
Don't stop doing good because God is aware of what happened to him.
Let's talk about this man first.
Because what he did now - assume he had not taken effort to buy this, to buy that,
to clothe the man, to get him to the bathroom and wash him,
there is no way we can see this man today.
He would not be able to come inside.
We would not be able to talk today about this man's predicament and the lesson we learnt.
I think for your charity, the ministry has to begin to establish people like this.
What we are even planning to do: Instead of our ministry to be doing it,
we want to have a kind of apostolic people.
If you are one of the apostolic, whatever the ministry can give you,
you will also be doing charity and every year we assess how far you have gone in charity.
The ministry can also be giving you money, some fund to be doing your charity there.
I think this man should be given 5 million to be starting the charity.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The 'Good Samaritan' To Receive 5 Million Naira For Works Of Charity
They should immediately because of position, the area where what he is doing there as a security;
there are many sick people that could not come.
There are many sick people when they get here, they are too sick; they cannot come in.
Some people, after the healing, they don't have money to go home.
Not of all them can reach us but the security there, he is there to quickly help them.
Immediately, get that cheque written and let him give testimony and let the world see.
5 million naira.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
And not only that - we want to know, you that has been doing charity, where are you living?
Are you leaving comfortably?
I am very happy.
We people of God are very happy to see a man like this in the house of God, working for God.
Not working for his pocket.
Wonderful.
All over the world, we want to have you over there.
If you are into charity, what can we do to support you and to showcase your case to the world?
I can be visiting you all over the world when you want to launch this charity.
We want to do it in a big way - scholarship given to deserving children,
supporting the widows and help the needy all over the world
and giving scholarships to the best candidates that deserve it.
Yes, rescue them.
Little kidnapped children, rescue them.
Go all the way to help mankind.
So that is it.
If you don't let this man know that it is good to do good,
irrespective of what comes, he will not do good again because he has seen pain,
affliction in doing good but we are saying, "No, no. Nothing can break me.
Nothing can separate me from doing good".
Stand up and tell your neighbour:
Nothing can separate me from doing good.
Can affliction?
Condemnation?
Even death?
What can separate you from doing good?
Say, nothing!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You may be seated.
Many, when they begin to recast their experiences in doing good in the past,
they will tell you that they will never do good again.
No, nothing can separate me from doing good.
Can affliction, poverty, imprisonment, infirmity?
Nothing can separate me because Jesus is good all the time.
Now brother, continue doing good until death.
Lucky Susu
Faith Bracelet Testimony
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When you see the light at the end of the tunnel...
Tell your neighbour: Continue doing good until you see light at the end of the tunnel.
The SCOAN Sunday Service.
I want to look at the picture of what has happened to our security personnel out there.
This is a similar thing that has happened, and I know revelation is coming.
I want to appreciate what they are doing.
This brother came here to prove to you that, 'Look, there is Godliness in them.
There is care, there is love'.
Please support them.
Any time you come, try to understand that they have many people to attend to.
Don't begin to look at them, don't just talk to them anyhow.
You have to be patient.
They need patience, endurance and perseverance from you.
You have to persevere and be patient because they attend to thousands of people.
It's not only you. If you just come to them, be patient.
Don't be in a hurry. If you are in a hurry meeting them, you may find them very tough.
It's nature.
Appreciate what they are doing.
This is one out of thousands that is going on.
They are many; they have done a lot.
So please, my message to you once again:
What you have passed through is as it should be by divine will.
The SCOAN Sunday Service.
They were not to destroy or kill you but to prepare you.
Look at where you are today.
Take this message from me.
Tell your neighbour:
What you are passing through is as it should be by divine will.
They are not to kill or destroy you but to prepare you for the challenges ahead.
Ask any great leader, they will tell you what they went through.
Read about the apostles in the Bible - you will see clearly that they saw darkness.
That was why they were able to maintain the good day they had that made them apostles.
Experience is the best teacher.
Thank you very much.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Opposite is the case now. What you were expecting - for the prophet to give to someone
who is testifying of prison is now given to a Good Samaritan.
What does that mean to you?
It means, there is a journey ahead.
He still has some journey to pass through
before he begins to experience that comfort he is expecting.
He said he was pushing the trolley.
I was pushing the trolley in the past.
The market he is talking about, I was there in the past.
Those who have read some story about me...
It was in the midst of all this that the Lord took me to the place where He could use me.
The SCOAN Sunday Service.
STANDARD FOR LIFE
You have seen during the service that the man of God addressed the issue of the brother
that was in the post of security service, helping the needy.
They meet thousands of these people during the course of their duty.
People in need come to the security post asking for help.
We saw the good work he did today by helping that man who was stranded.
And the man of God said live that he has taken the promise
to bless this man with this cheque of 5 million naira
to encourage him, to support him to go and do the good work.
The Bible says, the works of charity and works of righteousness go together.
When the man of God saw that, now he encourages this brother by giving him as he promised
that cheque of 5 million naira to encourage him to go and do the good work
in the ministry of charity to help the needy.
Thank You, Jesus.
The 'Good Samaritan'
A SCOAN Security Personnel
Viewers all over the world, partners all over the world, this is the contribution
the man of God promised to give him - that cheque of 5 million naira.
Brother, I hand over the cheque from the prophet to encourage you for the good work.
5 million naira cheque.
A SCOAN Security Personnel
Receives A Cheque Of 5 Million Naira
Praise the Lord!
My name is Chuks Onwago from the Security Department at The SCOAN.
I thank God today for the man of God's promise
to give me a cheque of 5 million naira for the works of charity.
I never expected this.
I was just discharging my duty as normal.
I never knew that this kind of blessing would fall upon my life today.
I give God the glory!
Mr Chuks, A SCOAN Security Personnel
Receives A Cheque Of 5 Million Naira
I promise God Almighty that I will continue the works of charity I normally do at my duty post.
I will not cease and make sure that I reach out to the needy.
I give God the glory for appreciating my effort.
I thank God Almighty!
Mr Chuks, A SCOAN Security Personnel
Receives A Cheque Of 5 Million Naira
TT Monica Asefa 21/0918
RV: Mel Flowers 03/11/2018